

PROFILE

I am a master's student at the University of British Columbia, Canada. I aim to build Al-driven software products +/ components to deal with the problems of both individuals and communities. Currently, I am working on different Topic Modeling algorithms and Text Classification techniques for handling software development issues faced by application developers. I am also designing an interactive analytical tool for different customizable Neural Network architectures.

Other than being a researcher, I mentor, motivate, and supervise young underprivileged undergrads who aim to become stellar researchers.

CONTACT

PHONE:

+1-250-899-6971

WEBSITE

mohammad-abdul-hadi.github.io

FMAII:

mohammad.hadi@ubc.ca

KEY ATTRIBUTES

- Determined to make a difference in individual and community
- Fastidious
- Patient, approachable
- Susceptible to suggestion +/ criticism
- Always on my way to building a rich repertoire of diverse skillset and interests

MOHAMMAD ABDUL HADI

Graduate Research Assistant

EDUCATION

University of British Columbia, Canada

MS in Computer Science (Sep 2019 – Present) Awards: Graduate Dean's Entrance Scholarship

Research Focus: Transfer Learning + Unsupervised Learning (NLP)

North South University, Bangladesh

BSc in Computer Science and Engineering (May 2014 – April 2018) Vice Chancellor's Gold Medal (Topper) + Summa Cum Laude Awards: Full Scholarship + Senior Research Grant

CGPA: 3.99/4.00

RECENT WORK EXPERIENCE

University of British Columbia – [Graduate Research and Teaching Assistant]Sep 2019 – Present

Proposed a Topic Modeling Algorithm; Completed an Empirical Study on text classification techniques, Designed an interactive visualization tool for a project of Archeology Department.

Niedner Inc. - [Software Engineer Intern]

Jan 2020 - Jun 2020

Modeling and optimisation of woven composite hydraulic tubes to reduce inservice defects and failures - Phase II (Led the visualization team)

Eastern University, Bangladesh – [Lecturer, Researcher]

Jul 2018 - Aug 2019

Led 2 research-projects: Studied correlation between use of smartphone applications and academic results of students; Built a platform to propose dynamic physician consultation fee structure incorporating scrutinized metrics.

North South University, Bangladesh – [Research Assistant]

Oct 2017 - Apr 2018

Project: Autonomous Robot Implementing Slam Algorithm (ARISA) with an approach to navigate blind people in unstructured environment

SKILLS

Written and Verbal Communication
Programming + Coding
Software Development
Object Oriented Design
Software Testing + Debugging
Problem Solving + Logical Thinking

